A key part of getting transitions to happen when we want
遷移が起きてほしいときに遷移させるのに重要になることは
them to is the design of reasonable cost functions.
適正なコスト関数の設計です
We want to penalize and reward the right things.
ペナルティを与え 良いことには報酬を与える必要があります
I'm going to work through an example of
コスト関数の設計について皆さんが考える可能性のある
one way you might think about designing a cost function.
1 つ方法の例を見ていこうと思います
Let's consider how we would design a cost function for vehicle speed.
車のスピードのコスト関数を設計する方法を考えてみましょう
On one hand, we want to get to our destination quickly,
早く目的地に着きたい
but on the other hand,
と思う一方で
we don't want to break the law.
法律に違反したくはありません
An essential quantity we have to control is the desired velocity of the car.
制御しなければならない必須の量は 車の希望する速度です
Some velocities are more beneficial,
有益な速度もあれば
some are even illegal.
違法な速度もあります
Let's fill in this graph and try to assign some costs to every velocity.
このグラフを埋めて各速度にコストを割り当ててみましょう
For the sake of simplicity,
簡潔にするために すべてのコスト関数の出力が
let's assume that all of the cost functions will have an output between zero and one.
0 と 1 の間であると仮定しましょう
We will adjust the importance of each cost function later by adjusting the weights.
後ほど重みを調整して各コスト関数の重要性を調整します
Let's say the speed limit for the road we are on is here.
道路の速度制限がここにあるとします
Well, we know that if we're going well above the speed limit,
この速度制限をはるかに超えている場合
that should be maximum cost.
最大コストとすべきです
And maybe we want to set
そして バッファを持たせるために
an ideal zero cost speed that's
速度制限をわずかに下回る
slightly below the speed limit so that we have some buffer.
理想的なゼロコスト速度の設定が必要かもしれません
And then we can think about how much we want to penalize not moving at all.
次に まったく動かないことに対してどのくらいペナルティを課すかを考えます
Obviously, not moving is bad,
動かないことは明らかに良くないことですが
but maybe not as bad as breaking the speed limit,
速度制限を破るほど悪くはありません
so we would put it here.
ですから ここに置きます
To keep it simple,
簡単にするために
we could just say there is a linear cost between zero and the target speed.
0 と目標速度との間に線形コストがあると言ってもよいでしょう
And since breaking the law is a binary thing,
法律に違反することは 2 択のことなので
let's just say any speed greater than or equal the speed limit has maximal cost.
速度制限以上のあらゆる速度は最大限のコストを持つことにしましょう
And again, we can arbitrarily connect these points with
そして再度 これらのポイントを線形関数で任意に結び
a linear function and the flat maximum cost for anything above the speed limit.
速度制限を超えるすべてに対し最大コストをフラットにすることができます
Now, in practice, we might actually want to parametrize some of
実際 正しい振る舞いが得られるまでこれらの量を後で調整できるよう
these quantities so that we could later adjust them until we got the right behavior.
これらの量のいくつかをパラメーター化する必要があるかもしれません
So first, we might define a parameter called Stop Cost for
まず ゼロ速度の場合の Stop Cost というパラメーターと
the zero-velocity case and a parameter called
おそらく時速数マイルになる buffer velocity
buffer velocity which would probably be a few miles per hour.
というパラメーターを定義します
Then, our overall cost function has three domains.
すると 全体のコスト関数は 3 つの領域を持ちます
If we're going less than the target speed,
目標速度未満で進む場合には
the cost function would look like this.
コスト関数はこのようになるでしょう
If we are above the speed limit,
速度制限を超える場合には
the cost is just one.
コストは 1 のみです
And if we are between,
間にある場合には
the cost would look like this. Awesome.
コストはこのようになるでしょう素晴らしい